<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stahlwalker</title>
    <description>Web design, digital marketing and a tech blog for web programmers.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 08:59:26 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 08:59:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Switching Industries</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;its-not-easy-as-1-2-3-a-b-c&quot;&gt;It’s not easy as 1 2 3, A B C.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Months after I completed my full stack web developer boot camp, I started applying for marketing roles within the tech industry. From my experience I can tell you, it’s not as easy as 1 2 3, A B C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following questions are some key takeaways and journey notes along the way, but don’t get me wrong, I had to build up my resume before making this switch. I took a 6-month web programming certificate to enhance my digital skillset and invest in my future. I believe every life changing move comes to fruition through persistency, you have to be willing to push yourself in order to make your goals a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-were-the-challenges&quot;&gt;What were the challenges?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/challenge.png&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
One of the biggest challenges I faced in this new career path was moving from one industry to the other and moving up the corporate ladder. While I had a lot of marketing experience it was limited to the healthcare field. I wanted to move into the tech industry and made that the sole focus of my journey. I also wanted to move up from specialist to manager, but not having that industry background put me a significant disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-was-the-biggest-surprise&quot;&gt;What was the biggest surprise?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d have to say the market. I was really surprised to see that the Chicago market was less likely to take a shot at someone with limited industry experience as opposed to the Bay Area which was incredibly more forth coming in their interviewing process. We all know that Silicon Valley is one of the biggest tech hubs in the United States, but Chicago is still a booming location. I really didn’t expect to have to relocate in order to achieve my goal. Out of 18 companies I interviewed with only 3 were located in Chicago, leaving me wondering if I was going to uproot and move out west.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe the Chicago market is still dated in the sense that they are more segmented as opposed to the Bay Area where they are more open minded to individuals who can bring something new to the table. In Chicago, it’s really about checking off the main 3 boxes, years of experience, desired field, and position specific. For example, if they are looking for a content marketing manager in Chicago, they want someone that is a content marketing specialist most likely with management experience in x amount of years. The idea of taking on the broader more jack of all traits “marketing specialist” isn’t the desired goal. Just because your bullet point experiences state you do content management, your title doesn’t and can weigh heavy in the automated systems decision to move your further. That’s where automated systems can really play a factor in getting your foot in the door. Which leads me to my next point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-was-the-most-eye-opening-during-the-interviewing-process&quot;&gt;What was the most eye opening during the interviewing process?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most eye-opening takeaway from 4 months of interviewing was the referral process. Not only was it a huge advantage, it was something I didn’t pay enough attention to and now highly recommend that if you know someone, somewhere, you ask for a referral. This typically bypasses the first round of automated systems that review your candidacy and gets you to an actual person. Once, I figured this out, my phone was ringing, and I was off to the races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-it-all-mean&quot;&gt;What’s it all mean?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to sum it up, switching industries is incredibly hard and the markets may not all be the same. Prepare yourself for the unexpected but highly use your resources around you. If you have someone within the organization that can refer you, I promise you, you’ll move the chains a bit further. I kept at it and pushed until I found the job that kept me local and in the desired industry, I wanted to be in. I did this through persistency. I now work at HERE Technologies a global tech company and am truly excited to see where this next chapter in life leads. It wasn’t the easiest process to go through, the odds were highly against me, but I used the resources around me and the strengths I built up to get the job I wanted. Which is all part of the #MASTERPLAN &lt;img src=&quot;/img/Here.png&quot; alt=&quot;HERE&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.here.com/en&quot;&gt;HERE Technologies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: 'Bradley Hand';&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/switch-industries</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/switch-industries</guid>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>healthcare</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        <category>industry</category>
        
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You a Yes Man?</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;back-at-it-and-it-feels-so-good&quot;&gt;Back at it and it feels so good:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been lost in translation for the past couple months as I’ve put my career goals ahead of my message. While I’ve been focusing on career growth these past four months, I’ve noticed one attribute from senior leaders that I find truly beneficial for anyone looking to move up the corporate ladder and that’s becoming a yes man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/corp-ladder.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
There is a fine line between being a yes man and allowing yourself to be walked over but I’ve had the pleasure of working under someone I truly feel owns the yes man role and does it right. Being a yes man comes with the attitude that no matter what it is you’ll find a way to get it done. In every job there are continuous asks and more responsibilities added on a daily basis. A yes man takes those situations and succeeds while others may push back. A yes man focuses more on the needs of those you are serving versus their own. Being a yes man enforces that you can handle extreme pressures of the day-to-day job. It gives leadership faith that they don’t have to go to anyone else because when the ask you say “I’ll find a way to get it done.” The more you build on this trait the more trust you will have and with leadership and with your clients. Ultimately, it adds much more work on you, but in the long run you will have more to show for it. Imagine your review a year after you have dedicated your time to becoming a yes man, it will be filled with tasks that become larger and larger as the trust built over the fiscal year. Once you have reached that status, leadership roles for yourself become a demand because the value you bring to the organization had significantly increased. As a leader it shows those that are reporting up to you, how things get done, how to handle adversity and how to achieve success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel fortunate that I’ve spent the past year learning from someone who crushes it on a regular basis, even when times get hard. We all have demanding needs and if you can look at the big picture you’ll see that being a yes man will come with its own rewards. I recently took this to heart and applied it to my career goals and it has been an absolute game changer. It resulted in a senior level position with a tech company and am thrilled for this new life changing journey. I’ve seen that being a yes man has not only improved the relationship with my clients but internally with fellow teammates. And while you don’t want to become the person people dump their work on, you definitely want to be the person people can come to for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/put-out-fire.png&quot; alt=&quot;Genie&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
As a marketer you put out fires on a regular basis, it comes with the territory, but being a yes man will only better equip you in the long haul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: 'Bradley Hand';&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/marketing/yes-man</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/marketing/yes-man</guid>
        
        <category>management</category>
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
        <category>yes-man</category>
        
        
        <category>Marketing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What HTML tag are you?</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-unexpected-interview-question-you-hope-to-hear&quot;&gt;The unexpected interview question you hope to hear.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently listened to a podcast called Front End Happy Hour in which they discussed interviewing questions and the most fascinating one was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;if-you-were-an-html-tag-what-would-you-be&quot;&gt;If you were an HTML tag what would you be?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s review all the different tags we have to choose from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.	&amp;lt;A&amp;gt; Anchor 
2.	&amp;lt;B&amp;gt; Bold
3.	&amp;lt;BIG&amp;gt; Large Type
4.	&amp;lt;BLOCKQUOTE&amp;gt; Indented Block
5.	&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt; Line Break
6.	&amp;lt;CENTER&amp;gt; Center Page
7.	&amp;lt;DEL&amp;gt; Deletion
8.	&amp;lt;DIV&amp;gt; Block-level Elements
9.	&amp;lt;EM&amp;gt; Emphasis
10.	&amp;lt;FONT&amp;gt; Font Attributes
11.	&amp;lt;HEAD&amp;gt; HTML Introduction
12.	&amp;lt;H1 H2 ….&amp;gt; Headers
13.	&amp;lt;HR&amp;gt; Horizontal Line
14.	&amp;lt;I&amp;gt; Italics
15.	&amp;lt;IMG&amp;gt; Image
16.	&amp;lt;LI&amp;gt; List Item
17.	&amp;lt;OL&amp;gt; Ordered List
18.	&amp;lt;UL&amp;gt; Unordered List
19.	&amp;lt;P&amp;gt; Paragraph
20.	&amp;lt;S&amp;gt; Strike Through
21.	&amp;lt;SMALL&amp;gt; Smaller Size Text
22.	&amp;lt;SPAN&amp;gt; Inline Content
23.	&amp;lt;STRONG&amp;gt; Bold
24.	&amp;lt;SUB&amp;gt; Subscript
25.	&amp;lt;SUP&amp;gt; Superscript
26.	&amp;lt;TABLE&amp;gt; Table
27.	&amp;lt;TD&amp;gt; Table Data Cell
28.	&amp;lt;TH&amp;gt; Table Header Cell
29.	&amp;lt;TITLE&amp;gt; Document Title
30.	&amp;lt;TR&amp;gt; Table Row
31.	&amp;lt;TT&amp;gt; Monospaced Type
32.	&amp;lt;U&amp;gt; Underline Text
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/div2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
The most common answer amongst the panel in this podcast was &amp;lt;DIV&amp;gt; because it can be used in so many different ways. I think it makes a ton of sense considering a &amp;lt;DIV&amp;gt; tag is a necessity when coding and can wrap around pretty all other tags. However, I feel the &amp;lt;DIV&amp;gt; tag is comparable to “more wishes” when asked if you have 3 wishes what would they be. There is always that one person that want’s more wishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think this is an excellent question and after much consideration I would go with &amp;lt;OL&amp;gt;. As someone that is extremely organized, I thought an ordered list would best describe me. I live by my reminders on my phone, they bring order to my personal and professional life. On any given day I average 15-20 reminders for a variety of lists. These lists vary from work projects, to birthday ideas for family and friends, to fantasy football and so on and so on. You know the expression you would feel naked without your phone, well, I feel that way about my lists. Without them, I’m lost, luckily, we live in a world where cloud computing allows me to store these lists and access them amongst many different devices. The cloud also gives me that safety net that even if I lost my device I would not lose my reminders list. Thank you, technology!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that begs the question what tag would you be and why?  Be specific because no one is going to give you more wishes. &lt;img src=&quot;/img/genie.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Genie&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://frontendhappyhour.com/&quot;&gt;Front End Happy Hours Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: 'Bradley Hand';&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/what-html-tag</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/what-html-tag</guid>
        
        <category>tag</category>
        
        <category>html</category>
        
        <category>interview</category>
        
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Contact Us Through Formspree</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;using-formspree-to-connect-with-visitors&quot;&gt;Using Formspree to connect with visitors:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a contact form is as simple as 4 steps with Formspree. Included is an example code that can be plugged into any html file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setup the html form&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a name attribute to every field&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submit the form and confirm your email address&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are done and should be receiving email notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;form action=&quot;https://formspree.io/your@email.com&quot;
      method=&quot;POST&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;name&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;input type=&quot;email&quot; name=&quot;_replyto&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;input type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Send&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/form&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve used Formspree on both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stahlwalker.org&quot;&gt;Stahlwalker&lt;/a&gt; and on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://lucasstahl.com/&quot;&gt;Interactive Resume&lt;/a&gt;. As a result, I receive an email notification anytime someone wants to connect. The good news it’s free until you start receiving more than 1000 submissions a day, then you can upgrade for $10 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatives to Formspree are sites like Firebase, however Formspree is ultimately easier to use due to it’s a contact form generator, taking in the input you desire.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://formspree.io/&quot;&gt;Formspree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: 'Bradley Hand';&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 12:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/formspree</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/formspree</guid>
        
        <category>formspree</category>
        
        <category>contact</category>
        
        <category>connect</category>
        
        <category>chat</category>
        
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SEO Checklist for Your Website</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;understanding-what-search-engines-look-for&quot;&gt;Understanding what search engines look for:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search Engine Optimization is the ability to enhance how accessibly a website is to users upon search. Digital marketers will highly recommend that your site’s SEO score be higher than your competition and luckily for you there are SEO checkers out there to help improve your score. Below are 41 steps to complete in order to make sure your site ranks highly in SEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Meta Title:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;The meta title of your page must have a length of 11 characters, do not exceed 70 characters. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Meta Description:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;The meta description of your page must not exceed 160 characters. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Most Common Keywords:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Make sure the keywords that appear most often on your page appear within natural sounding and grammatically correct copy. I found adding hidden paragraph tags with specific keywords hurt the overall SEO score. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keyword Usage:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Both title tag and meta-description tag are often used. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Related Keywords:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Are indexed keywords that rank your URL in the top 20 organic Google listings. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;h1 &amp;amp; h2 Heading Status:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Page should contain H1 and H2 headings but limit it to less than 10 H2 tags. This helps clarify the overall theme and supports subtitles.  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Robots.txt Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Robots.txt tells Googlebot and other crawlers what is and is not allowed to be crawled on your site.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sitemap Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;A sitemap is important because it informs search engines how many pages a website has and it improves the websites ability to be crawled. Sharing your sitemap xml file with Google Search Console https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/home?hl=en is a must for SEO. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Broken Links Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;This one is pretty straight forward, do not have links that are broken or sends visitors to a 404 page does not exist. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;SEO Friendly URL Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;In order for links to be SEO friendly, they should contain keywords relevant to the page's topic, and contain no spaces, underscores or other characters. You should avoid the use of parameters when possible, as they make URLs less inviting for users to click or share.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Image Alt Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Adding the alt tag to images is a way for users to know what the image is if there was an issue displaying, rather than looking at an image file thumbnail with no description. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Inline CSS Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Removing inline CSS properties can improve page loading time and make site maintenance easier. Use CSS files instead of inline styling. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Deprecated HTML Tags:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Deprecated html tags are old html tags that are not supported across all browsers. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Google Analytics Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Adding Google Analytics is a great way to track how users are viewing your website. Google Analytics are easy to install, Google provides you with the code to add in the HEAD tag. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Favicon Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;A favicon image is the main sites image. It is displayed on browser tab and when it's shared across social media channels. You will also notice that the favicon displays when the URL is shared through text messaging. Here is a link to a favicon generator that I prefer https://www.visiospark.com/apple-touch-icon-favicon-generator       
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Backlinks Checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Backlinks are any links to your website from an external site. Relevant backlinks from authority sites are critical for higher search engine rankings. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;JS Error Checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Errors with JavaScript files can lower score as well. Check the console log in the browser while visiting your site to see if any errors appear. This is a way to take note of what issues may be going on within your code. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Social Media Check:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;It's not enough that individual articles or written posts have sharing capabilities, users need to be able to share your site from any page easily. AddThis https://www.addthis.com/?utm_expid=12961876-41.5y4JCz2XROeUlBhVUbk2fg.0 is an excellent resource for implementing social media sharing. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;HTML Page Size Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTML size is the size of all the HTML code on your web page - this size does not include images, external JavaScript or external CSS files.    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;HTML Compression/GZIP Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTML compression plays an important role in improving website speed by finding similar strings within a text file and replacing them temporarily to reduce overall file size.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Site Loading Speed Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Pages that take longer than 5 seconds to load can lose up to 50% of users. Faster webpages result in higher traffic, better conversions and increased sales over slower loading pages.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Page Objects:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Http requests can slow down page loading, make sure the requests are working and limit the number of requests by adding actual files. For example, rather than using an image URL to another site, download the actual image and link to the file. The goal is to have lower than 20 http requests. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Page Cache Test (Server-Side Caching):&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Check if your page is serving cached pages. A page cache saves dynamically generated pages and serves the pre-generated (cached) page to reduce server load and site loading time (by avoiding the re-loading and execution of PHP scripts). Common caching methods are ZenCache and WP Rocket.      
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Flash Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;It is preferred to not use Flash because it is considered to be outdated technology. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Image Expires Tag Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Checks if your page is using an image expires tag, which specifies a future expiration date for your images. Users' browsers will see this tag and cache the image in their browser until the specified date (so that it does not keep re-fetching the unchanged image from your server). This speeds up your site the next time returning visitors arrive at your site and require the same image.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;JS &amp;amp; CSS Minification Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Using minification generators to improve load time. Here is a link to a good JS &amp;amp; CSS minifier https://www.minifier.org/.  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nested &amp;amp; Frameset Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Nested tables can also slow down load time and should be avoided. Frames create problems for users specifically for printing purposes. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Doctype Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Include the doctype at the top of your html to clarify which html you are using on your website. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;URL Redirects Checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Redirects often cause search engine indexing issues and can also lead to some minor loading delays. Google recommends removing or keeping redirects to a minimum.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;URL Canonicalization Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;You want to make sure that the URL for your site works with and without the www. For example https://www.stahlwalker.org and https://stahlwalker.org will both lead to the same place. This can be corrected in the DNS of your domain name from the provider you are using. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;HTTPS Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is one of the biggest of all tests. Make sure your site is secure, SEO increases dramatically for secure sites verses those that are not. If your URL is http and not https you have an issue.  I've written a blog post about securing your domain for free at https://stahlwalker.org/tech/jekyll-static-blogs            
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Safe Browsing Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Check if your website is identified as having malware or exhibiting phishing activity by Google's safe browsing API. Any site containing malware or suspicious for phising activity is seen as a threat to the online community and is often penalized by search engines. This test checks your website against regularly updated malware and phishing databases of problem websites. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Server Signature Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Check if your server's signature is ON. A server signature is the public identity of your web server and contains sensitive information that could be used to exploit any known vulnerability. Turning your server signature OFF is considered a good security practice to avoid disclosure of what software versions you are running.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Directory Browsing Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;If your server allows directory browsing you should disable it as it will lower your score. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Plaintext Emails Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Check your webpage for plaintext email addresses. Any e-mail address posted in public is likely to be automatically collected by computer software used by bulk emailers (a process known as e-mail address harvesting). A spam harvester can read through the pages in your site and extract plaintext email addresses which are then added to bulk marketing databases (resulting in more inbox spam). There are several methods for email obfuscation.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Media Query Responsive Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Adding media queries to your CSS files will improve mobile responsiveness and increase your sites SEO score.  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Microdata Schema Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Check if your website uses HTML Microdata specifications (or structured data markup). Search engines use microdata to better understand the content of your site and create rich snippets in search results (which helps increase click-through rate to your site).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Noindex Checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Do not use the noindex meta tag. This means that your webpage will be read and indexed by search engines.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Canonical Tag Checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;This tag specifies that the URL is preferred to be used in search results. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nofollow Checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Avoid nofollow tags and let search engines crawl your entire site. If you do want certain pages to not be crawled add the disallow directive to your robots.txt file.     
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;SPF records checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Check if your DNS records contains an SPF record. SPF (Sender Policy Framework) records allow email systems to verify if a given mail server has been authorized to send mail on behalf of your domain. Creating an SPF record increases email delivery rates by reducing the likelihood of your email being marked as spam.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;mark&gt;Source&lt;/mark&gt;  The following information was gathered from &lt;a href=&quot;https://toolbox.seositecheckup.com/&quot;&gt;SEO Toolbox&lt;/a&gt; which allows 15 free reports. This SEO toolbox gives your site an SEO score by percentage and ways to improve it. I found this site useful in improving &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stahlwalker.org&quot;&gt;Stahlwalker’s&lt;/a&gt; initial score of 88% to 96% once the recommended improvements were met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/metaDescript.png&quot; alt=&quot;Stahlwalker.org&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://toolbox.seositecheckup.com/&quot;&gt;SEO Toolbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minifier.org/&quot;&gt;JS &amp;amp; CSS minifier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.addthis.com/?utm_expid=12961876-41.5y4JCz2XROeUlBhVUbk2fg.0&quot;&gt;AddThis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visiospark.com/apple-touch-icon-favicon-generator/&quot;&gt;Favicon &amp;amp; Apple Touch Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/home?hl=en&quot;&gt;Google Search Console&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: 'Bradley Hand';&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 09:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/marketing/SEO</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/marketing/SEO</guid>
        
        <category>seo</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        <category>website</category>
        
        <category>checklist</category>
        
        
        <category>Marketing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Include in Your Website's Footer</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-needs-for-every-footer&quot;&gt;4 Needs for every footer:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you have your footer at the bottom of your page, right? If not, here is a link to learn how to create a &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/couple-takes-sticky-footer/&quot;&gt;sticky footer&lt;/a&gt;. You should feel pretty good by this point because making your footer stick to the bottom of your website is easier said than done. Now you need to know what content should be included in your footer. The basics to include are the year created and a link that drives visitors back to your home page, but there is so much more. Listed below are 4 great additions for every footer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Adding a like to the About page is a must because Google Analytics tell you that the About page is one of the most if not the most visited site on any page. If you don’t have one, create one, and if you have one add it to your footer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Contact is another must for your footer. Think about your call to action, for every page there should be some sort of call to action. Having your contact page on the footer increases your call to action across all pages. It also increases the user experience because if your site has a large amount of content scrolling all the way back to the nav bar is not ideal. Having a contact at the bottom gives the user access from both the nav and the footer encompassing your entire site. This makes it harder for users to say they didn’t know how to connect with you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Privacy Policy and Terms of Use are additional needs for every site because it gives the site owner the opportunity to express how they are using their site to collect data. It’s important to let your visitors know where they can read up on your sites privacy policy because collecting individual’s data without informing them can lead to legal issues later down the road. Adding the privacy policy to the footer is a best practice and incredibly important. Regarding Terms of Use, I lumped these two together because they almost go hand-in-hand. Terms of Use is another great section for explaining how you are using third parties such as Google Analytics to collect data. Additionally, there are great free generators out there for building privacy policy html files and terms of use html files. Once you have those files you can add them to whatever project you are working on. I have added them in the resource section below.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One that isn’t required but is a nice touch is a Site Map. Every page should have an XML site map file that exists in the root directory of your project. Once again there is a generator for creating a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xml-sitemaps.com/&quot;&gt;Site Map XML&lt;/a&gt;. However, we are not talking about the actual XML file rather an html file that mirrors the XML file but fits in the design of your website. Companies that have excellent site maps are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/sitemap&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nm.org/site-map&quot;&gt;Northwestern Medicine&lt;/a&gt;. A site map lists all pages on your website and is used by search engines to crawl over your website in order to track how many pages you have. Once you have created this site map you should also add it to Google Search Console, so that Google knows your site has it. Adding a site map helps with the SEO (Search Engine Optimization) of your website. Note, you want to make sure it updates if you add pages, typically the generator will account for this, but confirm it once you build out a new page or add a new post if your posts exist on their own pages.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/bundesligafanatic.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/honorable_mention.png?fit=751%2C357&quot; alt=&quot;Some Title&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honorable mention goes to social media and search bar. While I don’t think having your social media in the footer is a must, it definitely needs to be somewhere in your site, so a footer is as good a place as any. Adding a search bar is a nice touch, it gives users the ability to search content specific to your site, however, I find the user experience to be better suited for the nav bar at the top of your site, rather than the bottom. It doesn’t hurt to have both, but by then your footer may start to be a little too cluttered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple resources to help improve your footer’s reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://privacypolicygenerator.info/&quot;&gt;Privacy Policy Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://termsfeed.com/&quot;&gt;TermsFeed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/couple-takes-sticky-footer/&quot;&gt;CSS Sticky Footer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xml-sitemaps.com/&quot;&gt;Site Map XML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: 'Bradley Hand';&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/footer</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/footer</guid>
        
        <category>footer</category>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
        <category>terms</category>
        
        <category>about</category>
        
        <category>contact</category>
        
        <category>site-map</category>
        
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips to Creating a Successful Blog with Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;jekyll-static-site-generator&quot;&gt;Jekyll Static Site Generator:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had prior experience with blogging platforms, such as Blogger and WordPress, but the recent launch of &lt;a href=&quot;https://stahlwalker.org/&quot;&gt;Stahlwalker.org&lt;/a&gt; was my first attempt and creating a blog from scratch and using Jekyll helped. 3 tips to know before attempting to use Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be familiar with the command line as you will use it to run your server and if you don’t have ruby gems installed on your computer will have to do so. After Jekyll is installed there are a number of tutorials on YouTube that can help guide you through, but the one that I found to be the most helpful is on Udemy, called Jekyll: make fast, secure sties and blogs with Jekyll. This course has 29 lectures under 3 hours of material and afterwards you will have a working Jekyll blog.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Have a GitHub account. One of the best features with Jekyll is its integration with GitHub. Since, Jekyll works with GitHub you can publish your blog for free instead of going through Digital Ocean, Amazon S3, or Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Additionally, Cloudflare works with GitHub pages and Jekyll in order to help make domains secure. Creating an account with Cloudflare and then changing the DNS of the custom domain that you purchased to reflect GitHub’s DNS can turn any “Username&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.github.&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;io/appName” into a secure website. I spent a lot of time looking into SSL keys through Digital Ocean and Let’s Encrypt only to find this simpler solution with Cloudflare. The best part about it, it’s free. With Digital Ocean, I was creating droplets that would charge roughly 10 cents a day on top of a $5 a month fee.  It also required way more knowledge of the command line because it integrated Nginx, but that is a tale for another time. Long story short, Cloudflare integrated with GitHub and Jekyll can take your blog post one step further than the initial publishing feature GitHub has to offer. Sure, there are ways of publishing with a CNAME on GitHub, however you’ll notice your site isn’t secure and you have an “!” prior to your URL. &lt;img src=&quot;https://encrypted-tbn0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcQEGwja5X_u_swFYdUwFGqS8RtjR5Kh_B1mpRgv_oVEtD7K0kMZsQ&quot; alt=&quot;Some Title&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt; With the way web servers are cracking down on sites that are not secure, it’s important to make sure yours is from the beginning. Imagine all your hard work building a blog, publishing content for 2-3 years, only for Chrome to shut it down or require you purchasing an SSL Key for $75 a year. Save yourself the hassle and get it through Cloudflare, protect your site right out of the gates.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple links to help get you started on creating your first Jekyll Blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Install and Walkthrough&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/static-website-generator-fast-secure-sites-blogs-with-jekyll/learn/v4/overview&quot;&gt;Udemy Jekyll Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: 'Bradley Hand';&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 08:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/jekyll-static-blogs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/jekyll-static-blogs</guid>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>secure</category>
        
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who Has Questions???</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;dont-give-up-on-stack-overflow-just-yet&quot;&gt;Don’t give up on Stack Overflow just yet:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      I took the plunge a month and asked my first question on stack overflow. If there was ever a time to do it, it was now. I had been fiddling around with footers for far too long. They always seem to work one way and not the other. I’d get them to work on one website and then using the exact same CSS styling would fail horribly. Wanting answers, I went to stack overflow and searched “sticky footers”, there I found a ton of responses with a bunch of different methods for styling footers. After attempting a few with no success, I decided to ask the coding community and share the example I was working on. What happened after that completely surprised me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![Figure 1-1](img/stack.png &quot;Figure 1-1&quot;){:style=&quot;float: right;margin-right: 7px;margin-top: 7px; border-radius: 50%;&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      Stack Overflow has a system in which users can gain positive or negative interactions through either an up or down vote for answered questions. In an online boot camp I took through Udemy, the instructor mentioned that future employers will look at your rating on Stack Overflow to see whether it’s positive or negative. Think of it as likes, the more likes you have the better coder you are, because it means other coders are authenticating that your advice helped them. Sounds great right, but there is also a downvote, and coders can mark your feedback as unhelpful. Someone with a lot of negative reviews would definitely be a red flag for potential employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://t3.ftcdn.net/jpg/00/70/95/32/240_F_70953284_ddg71pEeAAF3Ma8LnA59dU6gCMV9HQyl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Some Title&quot; style=&quot;float: left;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
      I would also like to mention there is a specific way of entering code that if you are not familiar with Stack Overflow you need to be prior to asking questions. You can’t simply copy and paste code from an editor, you have to indent four times which makes a block in your post for code. There are more of these tips you can review at &lt;a href=&quot;http://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/251361/how-do-i-format-my-code-blocks/&quot;&gt;Stackoverflow.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      Back to the story, so I asked my very first stack overflow question and was immediately hit with downvotes to put it mildly. Programmers suggested I look up the question first before asking, which I did, but what I really found interesting was the ability to put a question on hold by other programmers. Shortly after the handful of downvotes I received, my question was placed on hold until I could provide more information. I went through the process of adding more content to the question but the damage was done. I did have a couple coders give suggestions on how to fix the sticky footer, which I thought was helpful but didn’t solve my issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      The key issue here is that everyone codes differently and there are plenty of different ways to place a sticky footer. You want to be able to utilize stack overflow as a resource but run the risk of being dinged for asking. Now there was definitely a learning curve here and my advice is to be as elaborate as possible and try to condense your question to one. People who ask too many questions run the risk of being flagged, put on hold or worse, the dreaded downvote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      After this experience I started asking instructors and teaching assistants how they utilize stack overflow and all of them stated they had never even asked a question, in all their years of coding. They also mentioned that they didn’t even know how to add code to the question. So, is Stack Overflow better off as a resource? I don’t believe so, much like anything there will be individuals in the community that are harsher critics, but there will also be those willing to help. For the handful of downvotes I received, I also had a couple individuals attempt to solve my question and one very responsive coder. After explaining, that I’m still learning the ins and outs of Stack Overflow, he spent time answering my questions, which goes to show that this application really can benefit people just don’t be surprised if you come across a couple harsh critics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      One of the first things they teach you when you begin your coding journey, is Google everything.  Google is your friend, search everything and anything. Who would have thought asking a simple question could lead to all this? Next time I’ll be better prepared and hopefully you will to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: 'Bradley Hand';&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/stack-overflow</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/stack-overflow</guid>
        
        <category>question</category>
        
        <category>footer</category>
        
        <category>stack-overflow</category>
        
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Oh My Metadata</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;avoiding-the-rabbit-hole&quot;&gt;Avoiding the rabbit hole:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to set the record straight right away and save you a lot of time, be aware of social cache. After implementing the share functionality, I made the mistake of testing my blog posts with Facebook, Twitter, and LinkedIn. I encountered a number of issues along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the share functionality worked. The problem existed with the display, I wasn’t sharing the blog post image or post description, rather the websites main image and description.  After researching the web, I found that I needed to add metadata to specifically call out the meta content. I had to add metadata to include page title, description, URL, and image.  Adding metadata was just the beginning of my decent, I had to use Facebook Open Graph Tags as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to use open graphs, I had to register with Facebook as a developer. Once I registered I was given a “app_id” which had to be added to the meta tag.  After I added the app id on the meta tag, I was able to validate with Facebook in their &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/tools/debug/&quot;&gt;Sharing Debugger&lt;/a&gt;. The sharing debugger confirmed how my shared post would look, and it was accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hooorayyyy, but wait, what about Twitter?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter follows a similar path; however, you do not need to obtain a developer app id. You can preview your shared post at their &lt;a href=&quot;https://cards-dev.twitter.com/validator&quot;&gt;Twitter Card Validator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching how to add the metadata was easy, not knowing social sites cache your initial post was the biggest hurdle to cross. Ultimately it disrupted any further attempt to share. Even if I went back and deleted the previously shared post via Twitter, LinkedIn or Facebook, the next time I shared that post it populated the same incorrect post. That means, I was missing the image that corresponded with the post image, and the description, even though both validators we correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that whenever I upload a new blog, Facebook’s sharing debugger needs to scrape the URL to obtain the meta tags and display it correctly. If I do not scrape each new blog post, Facebook will not recognize it and will not share it properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key takeaway, for testing purposes, make sure you have completed your post before sharing. Once it has been shared, social media platforms will cache it and you won’t be given the opportunity to correct it. It’s important to know that as long as you have the metadata and open graphs your followers or visitors will have no problem sharing your posts. Without metadata the share ability is limited to your overall site, which will jeopardize your blog posts. Do you really want to share the same image and description over and over again? Metadata even with its hurdles and endless rabbit holes to climb down is an absolute must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: 'Bradley Hand';&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 11:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/meta-data</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/meta-data</guid>
        
        <category>metadata</category>
        
        <category>social</category>
        
        <category>facebook</category>
        
        <category>open-graphs</category>
        
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Road So Far...</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;here-is-what-ive-learned-so-far&quot;&gt;Here is what I’ve learned so far:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the last 4.5 months attending a Northwestern University Web Programming Boot Camp and here are a couple key takeaways for those thinking about becoming a web developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While attending this boot camp, I have been doubling down on Udemy courses to further understand the why behind the how.  Northwestern does a good job of showing you how to code but a poor job of explaining the why we use different programming languages.  Northwestern alone wasn’t enough, and the idea that it’s for beginners is incredibly misleading.  For those looking to learn web programming, I’d suggest taking an online boot camp on Udemy for $20 versus the financial investment of a physical six-month program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could go back and do things over again, I would spend more time building my foundation prior to starting. There are hundreds of resources out there but I highly recommend Udemy. The ability to bookmark your notes and have lifetime access is a great reference. You also get certificates for completing courses which you can showcase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pros regarding Northwestern fall on the workload.  Students are forced to put in the work at an incredibly fast pace. With online boot camps students can learn at their own pace, it doesn’t work that way with a six-month program. Learning at your own pace can drag depending on your availability. It’s much easier to get to the assignment later when it doesn’t actually have a due date. Also, having the ability to work with others, on activities and projects is a major plus. Working with other students leads to better team building experiences and real-life scenarios. As a developer, you will be tasked to work on specific sections of a project with other developers, it won’t all be on your shoulders. Gaining that working experience is something you can only really do in a classroom setting. Northwestern also offers tutoring sessions weekly, which allows you to video conference with an expert to further enhance your skillset. These are all great resources one can only get from a physical boot camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I would change?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to know that because this program is only six months, they do run on a pretty strict schedule. If you think you are going to get all your questions answered you are mistaken. They simply do not have the time to stay on one subject for too long. That is where the how comes in and not the why. There simply isn’t enough time. I think less activities and more teaching would be better suited for this program. Often this program requires you to work on activities before actually explaining the topic, this can be difficult when it’s a new subject matter that has never introduced. My advice, bulk up on tutorials prior to taking a physical boot camp and I when I say bulk up, I mean a lot. The more you know the better because it is definitely not a beginner’s course. Lastly, enroll in an online boot camp that mirrors the boot camp you are taking in order to get the why and not just the how. Take it from someone who has spent the last couple months playing catch up with online tutorials and attending “office hours” before each class, it would have made learning easier if I was self-teaching through an online boot camp that ran parallel with Northwestern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s amazing that we have these tutorials readily available for us and if you are like me, you’ll find yourself with a never-ending wish list of tutorials once you get going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: 'Bradley Hand';&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 02:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/my-journey</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/my-journey</guid>
        
        <category>boot-camp</category>
        
        <category>udemy</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>northwestern</category>
        
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
