<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stahlwalker</title>
    <description>Web design, digital marketing and a tech blog for web programmers.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 07:30:56 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 07:30:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>iOS App Development</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;announcement&quot;&gt;Announcement:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike other blog posts, this isn’t in relation to marketing tips or tutorial blog posts, but a new section regarding announcements. My goal is to update you all with news regarding upcoming learnings whether it’s in web development or digital marketing. With that said, I’m happy to announce I’ve been building upon my iOS app development as one of my 2020 goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve taken a handful of courses recently from CodeWithChris that are free and available in the resource section below. I’ve also enrolled in a Udemy course The Complete iOS App Development Bootcamp by Dr. Angela Yu. Again you’ll find both in the resource section. If there was ever a time to really dive in and learn something new it’s now. From this, I plan to write more content in regards to what I learn along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/share/101WsWBUIcdV9bR3g=/&quot;&gt;The Complete iOS App Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/jniJeamcIUU&quot;&gt;How to Make an App for Beginners 2020 - CodeWithChris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/IIDiqgdn2yo&quot;&gt;SwiftUI - CodeWithChris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: &apos;Bradley Hand&apos;;&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/app-development/iOS-development</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/app-development/iOS-development</guid>
        
        <category>iOS</category>
        
        <category>app</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        <category>Xcode</category>
        
        <category>Swift</category>
        
        <category>brand</category>
        
        
        <category>App-Development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finding Your Marketing Compass</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;navigating-the-marketing-waters&quot;&gt;Navigating the marketing waters:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the different marketing titles out there in the industry, how do you know which one is right for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone that didn’t initially set out to become a marketer, I had to navigate the water with more of a learn on the fly approach. I wish I had the knowledge that marketing is where I wanted my career to end up earlier rather than later. I also wish I had the blueprints of how marketing teams are broken down because it’s difficult to redirect once you have gone down the rabbit hole, without taking a step back. Marketing teams are evolving, and branches have developed. Now people are going to school for these specific branches rather than marketing as a whole, so it’s important to know what these branches consist of before you dive in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let’s dive into the core elements surrounding marketing - digital, social, traditional, media relations, brand, product and revenue.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Brand.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: center;margin-right: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Digital Marketing&lt;/strong&gt; consists of marketing automation, email marketing, web development and content marketing. It’s also the responsibility of the digital marketing team to act as auditors for the company’s website. Often times content has a set and forget it feel, but some of that content has a lifespan that needs updating. Therefore a constant review to make sure outdated information or broken links don’t exist on your website is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social media&lt;/strong&gt; is pretty clear it represents a strategic marketing approach around social platforms. (See Media Relations below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traditional marketing&lt;/strong&gt; or sometimes called regional marketing consists of campaign management that support the organization and the internal clients for the external audiences. Now, I get, it’s confusing when you say internal clients to external audiences, so I’ll break it down further. Within any organization the marketing team is tasked with supporting teams internally to improve their offerings, services etc… which then benefits the external audiences. This isn’t internal communications; you aren’t looking to educate coworkers. Your clients are your coworkers and you’re improving their services. I’ve spent a large part of my career marketing in the healthcare industry, so I’ll break it down as follows; the internal clients were the doctors for a specific service line (let’s say orthopedics), and I was tasked with promoting their services to the external audiences (patients), to boost referrals/visits which then increased revenue (ROI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media relations&lt;/strong&gt; are individuals within the marketing team that work with media outlets such as news agencies to handle press releases and newsworthy events. They play a major factor when a crisis happens, trying to get in front of the negative news before it harms the organization. They are also there to promote the positive news and monitor what is being said throughout different media channels. Note the media relations team usually work closely with the social media teams because they will source the news through social eventually, so it’s important to be in lock step with one another. The difference between media relations and social media is, media relations will be doing the journalist work that social media marketers will not. Media relations will interview, quote and publish with other news outlets to voice the organizations opinions. Social media marketers will share these stories on social platforms for exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brand&lt;/strong&gt; is probably the most creative of all because it sets the standard for the companies look and feel. Usually the brand team creates guidelines for the organization that include assets to be used across the system. Without these guidelines the term rogue comes into effect. It’s never a good thing when there is no control over brand colors, logos, collateral, font etc.… it’s important for the brand team to play sheriff within the marketing department and organization as a whole. The reason I say they are most creative because they set the tone and often times are building brand awareness. Usually this consist of creating some sort of theme around your organization that can either stick forever, for a while or for a short period of time. Regardless, you get come up with that creative narrative for the entire organization not just a service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product marketers&lt;/strong&gt; are really the technical no it alls of the marketing world. It’s their job to know the product/service inside and out. They set the narrative for what a product/service offers. The narrative can then stem from the facts surrounding those products/service for other marketing departments to get creative. Typically when building out a campaign the product team is in there as fact checkers. If you are marketing the new iPhone and going to launch a global campaign, it’s important to have the stat sheet of upgrades such as the A11 chip or A12 chip. The product marketing team will be your best bet for the more technical questions around the product and do not dive into the creative messaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue marketing&lt;/strong&gt; can fall into traditional marketing but depending on how far along or how large your organization is you may want a team that focuses solely on larger enterprise accounts. Traditional marketing may want to focus on simply getting people’s foot in the door and revenue marketing will focus on those that have significant financial influence. It’s the comparison of a one off versus a contract. Simple way to put it, Revenue marketing is enterprise marketing with a much higher objective on increasing revenue. They have more ties to the sales teams and are targeting individuals that are further down the marketing funnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Mkt-Funnel.png&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: left;margin-right: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;So what are the takeaways?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to put your foot into each area a little bit, traditional marketing really captures all of this. However, if you have a passion for one over the other start with that out of the gate because once you go down a specific path it’s harder to crossover. When I got into marketing, I never really knew of the title web marketing manager. This is a role that would be in the digital marketing team and I absolutely love it. It’s someone that works on the website and is in lock step with the content team. Since, I’m a developer I have the capabilities of working in this role, but my background is not comparable to someone who has only worked in web marketing, which if an organization wants to hire someone with the best experience I will most likely lose out. That is one of the biggest impacts I see within these branches of marketing. What used to be a jack of a trades is getting pushed aside for someone that specializes solely in one area. As a marketer, I’ve done tons of social media marketing, but I’m not a social media marketing manager, therefore trying to be one I would be at a disadvantage. The upside to traditional marketing is having knowledge of all departments make you better suited for management. Those that only have experience doing one will not have the strengths to manage other departments under the marketing umbrella. A social media manager may not be well suited to manage the product marketing team as Director of Marketing. That’s where traditional marketing still has its strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a fine line of wanting to hone your craft and wanting to be knowledgeable of all strategic marketing efforts. Knowing you have options is fantastic but having an idea of what your career end game is will really put you down the correct path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, best of luck to you out there!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/marketing-jobs&quot;&gt;The Ultimate Guide to Marketing Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: &apos;Bradley Hand&apos;;&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/marketing/compass</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/marketing/compass</guid>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        <category>brand</category>
        
        <category>digital</category>
        
        <category>social</category>
        
        <category>revenue</category>
        
        <category>product</category>
        
        <category>media-relations</category>
        
        
        <category>Marketing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Expanding Your Scope</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;5-to-dos-that-will-make-your-manager-happy&quot;&gt;5 To-dos that will make your manager happy:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s common to have personal goals to help move you up the corporate ladder but have you thought about your managers goals? I’ve learned the quickest way to pave your path is to look at what your manager is doing and thinking outside the box on how you can enhance their workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often times we get caught up doing the day-to-day operations, waiting for our review to come along and expecting change. Did you know the definition of insanity is doing the same thing over and over again expecting change? So how do we make a change? How do we make sure when that review comes along the promotion follows? Here are 5 steps you can take to improve your work situation, all of which take the &lt;span style=&quot;color:red&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; out of the equation and focuses more on the &lt;span style=&quot;color:red&quot;&gt;WE&lt;/span&gt;. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/organized.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: left;margin-right: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
Step 1 – Get organized! Find some sort of tool that can collect all the projects you are working on, that way you can showcase what you have done, what you will be doing and ultimately a good idea of how much bandwidth you actually have. A personal favorite of mine is Smartsheet, it’s basically Microsoft Excel on steroids and can be accessed online and via app. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Step 2 – Take on projects that are outside of your wheelhouse. It’s never too late to learn new traits. In fact it’s almost better that you do look to expand upon your skillset. Taking on a project that you have little experience will challenge you and reward you, if you can buckle down and do the work. Not to mention, it’s another notch on your belt and ultimately your resume. I think back to the first time I developed an email nurture campaign, I had very little experience, so I took it upon myself to take an online courses to further educate myself on best practices. It’s great to say yeah, I can send out a marketing emails but learning how to develop a strategic email marketing campaign is a whole other achievement on its own, something I can now toot my own horn about. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Step 3 – Review the departments yearly goals so that you can best align your personal goals with that of the company’s. If email marketing isn’t an initiative on the year perhaps it’s not the best time to take up further education to better enhance your skills in that area. However, if improving organic social media marketing is one of your company’s main pillars then get involved. Ask to sit in on meetings, ask to shadow others with a higher knowledge of that specific field. Taking initiative to improve upon the company’s goals will never go unnoticed, it will most likely be encouraged. Obviously, making sure you have the bandwidth to do so and have a good understanding of step 1 so you don’t fall behind in your own projects. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Step 4 – Most importantly have insight into what your manager is working on. If you don’t have an understanding it means your line of communication needs improvement. Knowing what they are working on gives you the opportunity to take some of that workload off of their shoulders and ultimately expand upon your scope. Usually your manager is working on more senior level projects and as a result carry heavier workloads with higher recognition. Taking on some of their projects puts you in a position to say at the end of the year, this was outside of my usual responsibilities, but you wanted to better the department. It shows you are a team player and someone that the company can trust. If you find your manager coming up with ideas or saying “let’s have a think about doing…” then perhaps really do that. Think about what they are talking about and take it on as a project. Take a concept and bring it to life. Judge the realistic likelihood that it’s something that can be accomplished, don’t set yourself up for failure but take chances. If you are comfortable with the day-to-day operations that is fine, but if you are looking to move up the fastest way to do so is to expand upon what is right in front of you and your manager’s workload is the writing on the walls. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Step 5 – Attribute your success directly to your manager. When trying to move up the ladder the typical course requires you to either move into your manager’s position, supersede them or surpass them. By attributing your success to the support of your manager you can avoid burning bridges. Any good leader should want their direct reports to move up, it’s a statement to their management, but we all know that isn’t always the case. Sometimes taking a more political approach to cover all aspects is a great foot forward. It doesn’t hurt in the long run knowing that it will typically make all parties happy as long as you aren’t completely sucking up. You know the difference from complimenting and completely sticking your head up someone’s, you know… 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/success.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-right: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
While I don’t guarantee anything in life, I found in my experiences putting your best foot forward in the workplace starts with unburdening your managers workload. You’ll know this when you are a manager and have your direct reports doing the same. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As always, best of luck to you out there!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smartsheet.com/&quot;&gt;Smartsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: &apos;Bradley Hand&apos;;&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/marketing/expanding-scope</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/marketing/expanding-scope</guid>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        <category>management</category>
        
        <category>goals</category>
        
        
        <category>Marketing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You’ve Got Email</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;basic-essentials-for-a-successful-email-nurture-campaign&quot;&gt;Basic essentials for a successful email nurture campaign:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to develop a marketing email campaign, you have to break it down into three tiers, &lt;strong&gt;NEED&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;LEARN&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;PATH TO LOYALTY&lt;/strong&gt;. Now path to loyalty can mean a couple of different things, it could be path to paid, path to ambassador, basically it’s the end funnel of your desired outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I’m assuming you have some sort of working marketing automation software in place such as Marketo, MailChimp or HubSpot. I’ve added links to them to the related resource section but that would be the absolute first step above all. So, let’s get started… 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Need2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: left;margin-right: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
What is need? Need is a nurture campaign developed to target those that do not know about your product/service. It’s an educational drip campaign that guides customers through to sign up. At this point of the campaign it’s about awareness and improving open rates, reducing unsubscribe rates and sharing exciting offerings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Note that there is a fine line of over sharing, people do not want to be spammed so setting up a reasonable timeline with these emails is crucial. The ideal goal is around six emails in any nurture stream. An example of one that I’ve created follows a developer event and lasts the course of three weeks. Immediately after the event they are followed with a thank you for attending, then three days later information about what I’m offering. Then a week later some exciting news, followed by a comparison of plan offerings a week later, and ultimately a final reminder email. All of which, this email campaign lasts roughly three weeks. This span of three weeks is a good time frame that doesn’t annoy customers but keeps them engaged. Remember the goal isn’t to increase your unsubscribe list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Learn2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt; 
Following sign up these customers will be added to the learn campaign which is a retention stream. The goal of this nurture campaign is to keep people engaged and constantly learning about the benefits of your product/service. A great example is sharing advanced how-to tutorials. It’s not about selling the product, people are already invested, it’s about benefiting them so that they will ultimately become advocates/ambassadors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Loyalty.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: left;margin-right: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
Path to loyalty is the final stream in an email marketing campaign, it’s for those customers that are very active with your product/service. Those that may be on the brink of moving from a free plan to a pro plan. Usually a pro plan has a monetary value in which the email nurture campaign starts to achieve ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now that you have the basic setup or as I like to think about it as a solid foundation you can start brainstorming about what topics you want to cover. That is the tricking part, plugging the content into each nurture stream. As with any email campaign content is king. Luckily for us all we have the internet to help come up with great ideas. Another useful tip would be to watch some email marketing tutorials and see what other people created. From those videos you can dissect which emails should fall into your need, learn or path to loyalty streams. Lastly actually mapping out your stream with PowerPoint or say Mindjet software. I really enjoy Mindjet, so I’ve shared the link below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, best of luck to you out there!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketo.com/solutions/email-marketing/&quot;&gt;Marketo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchimp.com/&quot;&gt;MailChimp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hubspot.com/&quot;&gt;HubSpot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindjet.com/&quot;&gt;MindJet MindManager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: &apos;Bradley Hand&apos;;&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/marketing/email-marketing</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/marketing/email-marketing</guid>
        
        <category>email</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        <category>mail</category>
        
        <category>marketing-automation</category>
        
        
        <category>Marketing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One Small Step for Man…</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;hold-your-breath-we-have-an-os-update&quot;&gt;Hold your breath we have an OS update…&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or at least that is how it feels for me. As a new programmer, working with the terminal can be challenging. Take in consideration purchasing and/or updating to a new computer. Giving up all the installations from a previous computer can make anyone go crazy, even with time machine backups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I’m talking about mac users because that is my personal preference. I’m sure there are steps with other operating systems to ensure your data transfers over. Nevertheless, you feel as though you are starting from scratch when opening up the terminal. The real tricky part is when your computer has an update. In the time that I’ve been coding I’ve gone through a handful with Apple and the most recent being Mojave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/mojave.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I upgrade, I feel as though I run this risk of losing my ability to utilize this site. Working with Jekyll and Ruby Gems come with risks and rewards. I love the use of Jekyll’s static blog site however every time there is a new update, the gems require updating as well, all of which leaves me wondering if there is an expiration date on &lt;a href=&quot;https://stahlwalker.org/&quot;&gt;Stahlwalker.org&lt;/a&gt;. If you are wondering where I have been the past couple months it’s had a lot to do with complications between Jekyll, Mojave and GitHub. The first error I had was getting Jekyll to preview on localhost. Once I was able to preview my site to make changes, I was unable to push the code through to GitHub. I was dealing with a symbolic link issue and GitHub was asking me to remove the code from my site repository, however my editor would not allow me to delete it. So, what did I do to get the ball rolling again?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most programmers it started with Google, however after days of searching I had to do what I was taught as web developers and take a step back. So, a couple weeks went by, my reminder to fix the error kept getting pushed further and further down the line. The thought process that one day this site might deliver a 404 error &lt;img src=&quot;/img/404.png&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt; to all visitors because I either crashed it downloading someone’s recommendation via Stack Overflow or simply zero activity was rapidly keeping me up at night. After waiting and revisiting the issue, I resorted to putting my faith in Google again and I was able to come to the solution. I needed to add a .gitignore file to ignore my vendor files. This would avoid pushing the symbolic link to GitHub and sure enough &lt;strong&gt;IT WORKED&lt;/strong&gt;. Hallelujah I was back up and running again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still the notion of until next time lingers in the back of my mind because with all software comes updates and these major operating software updates are ticking time bombs. So, don’t be surprised, if you see me go months and months at end without a post. You’ll know the root cause if you start seeing the 404 error. That or it means I did it, I finally broke my site, at this point I’m beginning to think it’s inevitable. The positive outlook on this is with Google you can always find a way. I’d like to thank all the better programmers out there for saving me over and over again, I don’t know where I would be without your help. Thank you, Stack Overflow, and a special thank you to the developer community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/macos/&quot;&gt;Jekyll &amp;amp; macOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/stackoverflow.png&quot; alt=&quot;HERE&quot; style=&quot;float: center;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: &apos;Bradley Hand&apos;;&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/jekyll-and-macOS</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/jekyll-and-macOS</guid>
        
        <category>macOS</category>
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
        <category>stack-overflow</category>
        
        <category>mojave</category>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Switching Industries</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;its-not-easy-as-1-2-3-a-b-c&quot;&gt;It’s not easy as 1 2 3, A B C.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Months after I completed my full stack web developer boot camp, I started applying for marketing roles within the tech industry. From my experience I can tell you, it’s not as easy as 1 2 3, A B C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following questions are some key takeaways and journey notes along the way, but don’t get me wrong, I had to build up my resume before making this switch. I took a 6-month web programming certificate to enhance my digital skillset and invest in my future. I believe every life changing move comes to fruition through persistency, you have to be willing to push yourself in order to make your goals a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-were-the-challenges&quot;&gt;What were the challenges?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/challenge.png&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
One of the biggest challenges I faced in this new career path was moving from one industry to the other and moving up the corporate ladder. While I had a lot of marketing experience it was limited to the healthcare field. I wanted to move into the tech industry and made that the sole focus of my journey. I also wanted to move up from specialist to manager, but not having that industry background put me a significant disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-was-the-biggest-surprise&quot;&gt;What was the biggest surprise?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d have to say the market. I was really surprised to see that the Chicago market was less likely to take a shot at someone with limited industry experience as opposed to the Bay Area which was incredibly more forth coming in their interviewing process. We all know that Silicon Valley is one of the biggest tech hubs in the United States, but Chicago is still a booming location. I really didn’t expect to have to relocate in order to achieve my goal. Out of 18 companies I interviewed with only 3 were located in Chicago, leaving me wondering if I was going to uproot and move out west.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe the Chicago market is still dated in the sense that they are more segmented as opposed to the Bay Area where they are more open minded to individuals who can bring something new to the table. In Chicago, it’s really about checking off the main 3 boxes, years of experience, desired field, and position specific. For example, if they are looking for a content marketing manager in Chicago, they want someone that is a content marketing specialist most likely with management experience in x amount of years. The idea of taking on the broader more jack of all traits “marketing specialist” isn’t the desired goal. Just because your bullet point experiences state you do content management, your title doesn’t and can weigh heavy in the automated systems decision to move your further. That’s where automated systems can really play a factor in getting your foot in the door. Which leads me to my next point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-was-the-most-eye-opening-during-the-interviewing-process&quot;&gt;What was the most eye opening during the interviewing process?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most eye-opening takeaway from 4 months of interviewing was the referral process. Not only was it a huge advantage, it was something I didn’t pay enough attention to and now highly recommend that if you know someone, somewhere, you ask for a referral. This typically bypasses the first round of automated systems that review your candidacy and gets you to an actual person. Once, I figured this out, my phone was ringing, and I was off to the races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-it-all-mean&quot;&gt;What’s it all mean?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to sum it up, switching industries is incredibly hard and the markets may not all be the same. Prepare yourself for the unexpected but highly use your resources around you. If you have someone within the organization that can refer you, I promise you, you’ll move the chains a bit further. I kept at it and pushed until I found the job that kept me local and in the desired industry, I wanted to be in. I did this through persistency. I now work at HERE Technologies a global tech company and am truly excited to see where this next chapter in life leads. It wasn’t the easiest process to go through, the odds were highly against me, but I used the resources around me and the strengths I built up to get the job I wanted. Which is all part of the #MASTERPLAN &lt;img src=&quot;/img/Here.png&quot; alt=&quot;HERE&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.here.com/en&quot;&gt;HERE Technologies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: &apos;Bradley Hand&apos;;&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/switch-industries</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/switch-industries</guid>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>healthcare</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        <category>industry</category>
        
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You a Yes Man?</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;back-at-it-and-it-feels-so-good&quot;&gt;Back at it and it feels so good:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been lost in translation for the past couple months as I’ve put my career goals ahead of my message. While I’ve been focusing on career growth these past four months, I’ve noticed one attribute from senior leaders that I find truly beneficial for anyone looking to move up the corporate ladder and that’s becoming a yes man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/corp-ladder.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
There is a fine line between being a yes man and allowing yourself to be walked over but I’ve had the pleasure of working under someone I truly feel owns the yes man role and does it right. Being a yes man comes with the attitude that no matter what it is you’ll find a way to get it done. In every job there are continuous asks and more responsibilities added on a daily basis. A yes man takes those situations and succeeds while others may push back. A yes man focuses more on the needs of those you are serving versus their own. Being a yes man enforces that you can handle extreme pressures of the day-to-day job. It gives leadership faith that they don’t have to go to anyone else because when the ask you say “I’ll find a way to get it done.” The more you build on this trait the more trust you will have and with leadership and with your clients. Ultimately, it adds much more work on you, but in the long run you will have more to show for it. Imagine your review a year after you have dedicated your time to becoming a yes man, it will be filled with tasks that become larger and larger as the trust built over the fiscal year. Once you have reached that status, leadership roles for yourself become a demand because the value you bring to the organization had significantly increased. As a leader it shows those that are reporting up to you, how things get done, how to handle adversity and how to achieve success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel fortunate that I’ve spent the past year learning from someone who crushes it on a regular basis, even when times get hard. We all have demanding needs and if you can look at the big picture you’ll see that being a yes man will come with its own rewards. I recently took this to heart and applied it to my career goals and it has been an absolute game changer. It resulted in a senior level position with a tech company and am thrilled for this new life changing journey. I’ve seen that being a yes man has not only improved the relationship with my clients but internally with fellow teammates. And while you don’t want to become the person people dump their work on, you definitely want to be the person people can come to for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/put-out-fire.png&quot; alt=&quot;Genie&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
As a marketer you put out fires on a regular basis, it comes with the territory, but being a yes man will only better equip you in the long haul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: &apos;Bradley Hand&apos;;&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/marketing/yes-man</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/marketing/yes-man</guid>
        
        <category>management</category>
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
        <category>yes-man</category>
        
        
        <category>Marketing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What HTML tag are you?</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-unexpected-interview-question-you-hope-to-hear&quot;&gt;The unexpected interview question you hope to hear.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently listened to a podcast called Front End Happy Hour in which they discussed interviewing questions and the most fascinating one was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;if-you-were-an-html-tag-what-would-you-be&quot;&gt;If you were an HTML tag what would you be?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s review all the different tags we have to choose from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.	&amp;lt;A&amp;gt; Anchor 
2.	&amp;lt;B&amp;gt; Bold
3.	&amp;lt;BIG&amp;gt; Large Type
4.	&amp;lt;BLOCKQUOTE&amp;gt; Indented Block
5.	&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt; Line Break
6.	&amp;lt;CENTER&amp;gt; Center Page
7.	&amp;lt;DEL&amp;gt; Deletion
8.	&amp;lt;DIV&amp;gt; Block-level Elements
9.	&amp;lt;EM&amp;gt; Emphasis
10.	&amp;lt;FONT&amp;gt; Font Attributes
11.	&amp;lt;HEAD&amp;gt; HTML Introduction
12.	&amp;lt;H1 H2 ….&amp;gt; Headers
13.	&amp;lt;HR&amp;gt; Horizontal Line
14.	&amp;lt;I&amp;gt; Italics
15.	&amp;lt;IMG&amp;gt; Image
16.	&amp;lt;LI&amp;gt; List Item
17.	&amp;lt;OL&amp;gt; Ordered List
18.	&amp;lt;UL&amp;gt; Unordered List
19.	&amp;lt;P&amp;gt; Paragraph
20.	&amp;lt;S&amp;gt; Strike Through
21.	&amp;lt;SMALL&amp;gt; Smaller Size Text
22.	&amp;lt;SPAN&amp;gt; Inline Content
23.	&amp;lt;STRONG&amp;gt; Bold
24.	&amp;lt;SUB&amp;gt; Subscript
25.	&amp;lt;SUP&amp;gt; Superscript
26.	&amp;lt;TABLE&amp;gt; Table
27.	&amp;lt;TD&amp;gt; Table Data Cell
28.	&amp;lt;TH&amp;gt; Table Header Cell
29.	&amp;lt;TITLE&amp;gt; Document Title
30.	&amp;lt;TR&amp;gt; Table Row
31.	&amp;lt;TT&amp;gt; Monospaced Type
32.	&amp;lt;U&amp;gt; Underline Text
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/div2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Div&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
The most common answer amongst the panel in this podcast was &amp;lt;DIV&amp;gt; because it can be used in so many different ways. I think it makes a ton of sense considering a &amp;lt;DIV&amp;gt; tag is a necessity when coding and can wrap around pretty all other tags. However, I feel the &amp;lt;DIV&amp;gt; tag is comparable to “more wishes” when asked if you have 3 wishes what would they be. There is always that one person that want’s more wishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think this is an excellent question and after much consideration I would go with &amp;lt;OL&amp;gt;. As someone that is extremely organized, I thought an ordered list would best describe me. I live by my reminders on my phone, they bring order to my personal and professional life. On any given day I average 15-20 reminders for a variety of lists. These lists vary from work projects, to birthday ideas for family and friends, to fantasy football and so on and so on. You know the expression you would feel naked without your phone, well, I feel that way about my lists. Without them, I’m lost, luckily, we live in a world where cloud computing allows me to store these lists and access them amongst many different devices. The cloud also gives me that safety net that even if I lost my device I would not lose my reminders list. Thank you, technology!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that begs the question what tag would you be and why?  Be specific because no one is going to give you more wishes. &lt;img src=&quot;/img/genie.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Genie&quot; style=&quot;float: right;margin-left: 7px;margin-top: 7px; position: relative&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://frontendhappyhour.com/&quot;&gt;Front End Happy Hours Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: &apos;Bradley Hand&apos;;&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/what-html-tag</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/what-html-tag</guid>
        
        <category>tag</category>
        
        <category>html</category>
        
        <category>interview</category>
        
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Contact Us Through Formspree</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;using-formspree-to-connect-with-visitors&quot;&gt;Using Formspree to connect with visitors:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a contact form is as simple as 4 steps with Formspree. Included is an example code that can be plugged into any html file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setup the html form&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a name attribute to every field&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submit the form and confirm your email address&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are done and should be receiving email notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;form action=&quot;https://formspree.io/your@email.com&quot;
      method=&quot;POST&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;name&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;input type=&quot;email&quot; name=&quot;_replyto&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;input type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Send&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/form&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve used Formspree on both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stahlwalker.org&quot;&gt;Stahlwalker&lt;/a&gt; and on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://lucasstahl.com/&quot;&gt;Interactive Resume&lt;/a&gt;. As a result, I receive an email notification anytime someone wants to connect. The good news it’s free until you start receiving more than 1000 submissions a day, then you can upgrade for $10 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatives to Formspree are sites like Firebase, however Formspree is ultimately easier to use due to it’s a contact form generator, taking in the input you desire.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://formspree.io/&quot;&gt;Formspree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: &apos;Bradley Hand&apos;;&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 12:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/formspree</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/formspree</guid>
        
        <category>formspree</category>
        
        <category>contact</category>
        
        <category>connect</category>
        
        <category>chat</category>
        
        
        <category>Tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SEO Checklist for Your Website</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;understanding-what-search-engines-look-for&quot;&gt;Understanding what search engines look for:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search Engine Optimization is the ability to enhance how accessibly a website is to users upon search. Digital marketers will highly recommend that your site’s SEO score be higher than your competition and luckily for you there are SEO checkers out there to help improve your score. Below are 41 steps to complete in order to make sure your site ranks highly in SEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Meta Title:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;The meta title of your page must have a length of 11 characters, do not exceed 70 characters. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Meta Description:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;The meta description of your page must not exceed 160 characters. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Most Common Keywords:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Make sure the keywords that appear most often on your page appear within natural sounding and grammatically correct copy. I found adding hidden paragraph tags with specific keywords hurt the overall SEO score. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keyword Usage:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Both title tag and meta-description tag are often used. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Related Keywords:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Are indexed keywords that rank your URL in the top 20 organic Google listings. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;h1 &amp;amp; h2 Heading Status:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Page should contain H1 and H2 headings but limit it to less than 10 H2 tags. This helps clarify the overall theme and supports subtitles.  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Robots.txt Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Robots.txt tells Googlebot and other crawlers what is and is not allowed to be crawled on your site.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sitemap Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;A sitemap is important because it informs search engines how many pages a website has and it improves the websites ability to be crawled. Sharing your sitemap xml file with Google Search Console https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/home?hl=en is a must for SEO. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Broken Links Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;This one is pretty straight forward, do not have links that are broken or sends visitors to a 404 page does not exist. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;SEO Friendly URL Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;In order for links to be SEO friendly, they should contain keywords relevant to the page&apos;s topic, and contain no spaces, underscores or other characters. You should avoid the use of parameters when possible, as they make URLs less inviting for users to click or share.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Image Alt Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Adding the alt tag to images is a way for users to know what the image is if there was an issue displaying, rather than looking at an image file thumbnail with no description. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Inline CSS Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Removing inline CSS properties can improve page loading time and make site maintenance easier. Use CSS files instead of inline styling. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Deprecated HTML Tags:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Deprecated html tags are old html tags that are not supported across all browsers. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Google Analytics Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Adding Google Analytics is a great way to track how users are viewing your website. Google Analytics are easy to install, Google provides you with the code to add in the HEAD tag. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Favicon Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;A favicon image is the main sites image. It is displayed on browser tab and when it&apos;s shared across social media channels. You will also notice that the favicon displays when the URL is shared through text messaging. Here is a link to a favicon generator that I prefer https://iconifier.net/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Backlinks Checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Backlinks are any links to your website from an external site. Relevant backlinks from authority sites are critical for higher search engine rankings. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;JS Error Checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Errors with JavaScript files can lower score as well. Check the console log in the browser while visiting your site to see if any errors appear. This is a way to take note of what issues may be going on within your code. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Social Media Check:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;It&apos;s not enough that individual articles or written posts have sharing capabilities, users need to be able to share your site from any page easily. AddThis https://www.addthis.com/?utm_expid=12961876-41.5y4JCz2XROeUlBhVUbk2fg.0 is an excellent resource for implementing social media sharing. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;HTML Page Size Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTML size is the size of all the HTML code on your web page - this size does not include images, external JavaScript or external CSS files.    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;HTML Compression/GZIP Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTML compression plays an important role in improving website speed by finding similar strings within a text file and replacing them temporarily to reduce overall file size.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Site Loading Speed Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Pages that take longer than 5 seconds to load can lose up to 50% of users. Faster webpages result in higher traffic, better conversions and increased sales over slower loading pages.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Page Objects:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Http requests can slow down page loading, make sure the requests are working and limit the number of requests by adding actual files. For example, rather than using an image URL to another site, download the actual image and link to the file. The goal is to have lower than 20 http requests. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Page Cache Test (Server-Side Caching):&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Check if your page is serving cached pages. A page cache saves dynamically generated pages and serves the pre-generated (cached) page to reduce server load and site loading time (by avoiding the re-loading and execution of PHP scripts). Common caching methods are ZenCache and WP Rocket.      
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Flash Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;It is preferred to not use Flash because it is considered to be outdated technology. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Image Expires Tag Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Checks if your page is using an image expires tag, which specifies a future expiration date for your images. Users&apos; browsers will see this tag and cache the image in their browser until the specified date (so that it does not keep re-fetching the unchanged image from your server). This speeds up your site the next time returning visitors arrive at your site and require the same image.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;JS &amp;amp; CSS Minification Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Using minification generators to improve load time. Here is a link to a good JS &amp;amp; CSS minifier https://www.minifier.org/.  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nested &amp;amp; Frameset Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Nested tables can also slow down load time and should be avoided. Frames create problems for users specifically for printing purposes. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Doctype Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Include the doctype at the top of your html to clarify which html you are using on your website. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;URL Redirects Checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Redirects often cause search engine indexing issues and can also lead to some minor loading delays. Google recommends removing or keeping redirects to a minimum.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;URL Canonicalization Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;You want to make sure that the URL for your site works with and without the www. For example https://www.stahlwalker.org and https://stahlwalker.org will both lead to the same place. This can be corrected in the DNS of your domain name from the provider you are using. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;HTTPS Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is one of the biggest of all tests. Make sure your site is secure, SEO increases dramatically for secure sites verses those that are not. If your URL is http and not https you have an issue.  I&apos;ve written a blog post about securing your domain for free at https://stahlwalker.org/tech/jekyll-static-blogs            
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Safe Browsing Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Check if your website is identified as having malware or exhibiting phishing activity by Google&apos;s safe browsing API. Any site containing malware or suspicious for phising activity is seen as a threat to the online community and is often penalized by search engines. This test checks your website against regularly updated malware and phishing databases of problem websites. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Server Signature Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Check if your server&apos;s signature is ON. A server signature is the public identity of your web server and contains sensitive information that could be used to exploit any known vulnerability. Turning your server signature OFF is considered a good security practice to avoid disclosure of what software versions you are running.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Directory Browsing Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;If your server allows directory browsing you should disable it as it will lower your score. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Plaintext Emails Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Check your webpage for plaintext email addresses. Any e-mail address posted in public is likely to be automatically collected by computer software used by bulk emailers (a process known as e-mail address harvesting). A spam harvester can read through the pages in your site and extract plaintext email addresses which are then added to bulk marketing databases (resulting in more inbox spam). There are several methods for email obfuscation.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Media Query Responsive Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Adding media queries to your CSS files will improve mobile responsiveness and increase your sites SEO score.  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Microdata Schema Test:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Check if your website uses HTML Microdata specifications (or structured data markup). Search engines use microdata to better understand the content of your site and create rich snippets in search results (which helps increase click-through rate to your site).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Noindex Checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Do not use the noindex meta tag. This means that your webpage will be read and indexed by search engines.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Canonical Tag Checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;This tag specifies that the URL is preferred to be used in search results. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nofollow Checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Avoid nofollow tags and let search engines crawl your entire site. If you do want certain pages to not be crawled add the disallow directive to your robots.txt file.     
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;SPF records checker:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Check if your DNS records contains an SPF record. SPF (Sender Policy Framework) records allow email systems to verify if a given mail server has been authorized to send mail on behalf of your domain. Creating an SPF record increases email delivery rates by reducing the likelihood of your email being marked as spam.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;mark&gt;Source&lt;/mark&gt;  The following information was gathered from &lt;a href=&quot;https://toolbox.seositecheckup.com/&quot;&gt;SEO Toolbox&lt;/a&gt; which allows 15 free reports. This SEO toolbox gives your site an SEO score by percentage and ways to improve it. I found this site useful in improving &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stahlwalker.org&quot;&gt;Stahlwalker’s&lt;/a&gt; initial score of 88% to 96% once the recommended improvements were met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/metaDescript.png&quot; alt=&quot;Stahlwalker.org&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;related-resources&quot;&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://toolbox.seositecheckup.com/&quot;&gt;SEO Toolbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minifier.org/&quot;&gt;JS &amp;amp; CSS minifier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.addthis.com/?utm_expid=12961876-41.5y4JCz2XROeUlBhVUbk2fg.0&quot;&gt;AddThis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iconifier.net/&quot;&gt;Favicon &amp;amp; Apple Touch Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/home?hl=en&quot;&gt;Google Search Console&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-hope-this-was-helpful-and-feel-free-to-comment-with-suggestions-or-questions&quot;&gt;I hope this was helpful and feel free to comment with suggestions or questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;--man-of-stahl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(50, 126, 235); font-family: &apos;Bradley Hand&apos;;&quot;&gt;- Man of Stahl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 09:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/marketing/SEO</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/marketing/SEO</guid>
        
        <category>seo</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        <category>website</category>
        
        <category>checklist</category>
        
        
        <category>Marketing</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
